

## Agalic Rodriguez-Duboc

## MD, PHD IN DEVELOPMENTAL NEUROBIOLOGY

Trained as a general physician and passionate about research, I am currently finalizing my PhD dissertation in the field of cellular and molecular neuroscience. My research is focused on cerebellar development and apnea of prematurity.

agalic.rd@gmail.com

76000 Rouen, France

Date of birth 10/05/1990 https://agalic-rd.com/

French

## Languages

**French** 

Native language

Spanish

Native language

**English** 

Native proficiency

Norwegian

Intermediate (CEFR: B1)

Italian

Beginner (CEFR: A2)

German

Beginner (CEFR: A2)

#### **Assets**

Determination

Creativity

Curiosity

Autonomy

#### **Professional interests**

Molecular biology and signaling pathways

Neurosciences, neurology, psychiatry

Preventive medicine and public health

## Personal interests

Reading and literature

Painting and drawing

Knitting and crochet

Nature and sustainability

#### Education

From September 2019 to May 2023 PhD in Molecular and Cellular aspects of Biology Rouen University Mont-Saint-Aignan, France

Specialty in Neurosciences

From October 2019 to November 2019

**Certification in Animal Experimentation** 

Paris Descartes Paris, France

From September 2018 to June 2019 Master's in Research: Neurosciences (MSc) Rouen University Mont-Saint-Aignan, France

Molecular, Cellular, and Integrated Neurosciences - Cum Laude

October 2017

USMLE (United States Medical Licensing Examination) Step 1 National Board of Medical Examiners Philadelphia, PA, USA

From September 2011 to June 2017 Medical Doctor (MD)

PUCMM University Santiago, Dominican Republic

Magna Cum Laude

## Research Experience

From September 2019 to May 2023 **Doctoral Candidate** 

INSERM U1245 CBG Rouen, France

- Topic: "Cellular, molecular and vascular alterations induced by apnea of prematurity in the murine cerebellum."
- Advisor: Dr. Delphine Burel.

From January 2019 to June 2019

Master's Research Internship

Inserm U1239 DC2N Mont-Saint-Aignan, France

- Topic: "Effects of perinatal hypoxia on the expression of genes involved in oxidative stress.".
- Advisor: Dr. Delphine Burel.

From August 2015 to April 2017

**Medical Dissertation** 

Departamento de Investigación, PUCMM University Santiago de los Caballeros, Dominican Republic

- Topic: "Psychological factors associated with nicotine addiction in college students."
- Advisor: Dr. Zahíra Quiñones de Monegro.

From March 2014 to December 2014

Research Assistant Experience

Laboratory of Nanosciences, PUCMM University Santiago de los Caballeros, Dominican Republic

- Topic: "Hypercaloric effect of biofunctionalized carbon nanotubes as a photothermal agent on Staphilococcus aureus."
- Advisor: Dr. Oliver Pfaff.

## **Publications**

- Leroux S, Rodriguez-Duboc A, Arabo A, Basille-Dugay M, Vaudry D, Burel D. 2022. Intermittent hypoxia in a mouse model of apnea of prematurity leads to a retardation of cerebellar development and long-term functional deficits. Cell Biosci. 12(1):148.
- Rodriguez-Duboc A, Basille-Dugay M, Debonne A, Vaudry D, Burel D. Apnea of prematurity induces oxidative stress-mediated transcriptional changes in the murine cerebellum (in preparation).

#### **Posters**

**LARC Neurosciences 2019** Effects of perinatal hypoxia on oxidative stress-related gene expression in the murine cerebellum.

**JED EDNBISE 2022** Apnea of Prematurity induces molecular, cellular, and vascular alterations in the murine cerebellum: focusing on angiogenesis.

#### **Talks**

**JED EDNBISE 2021** Therapeutic potential of neurotrophic factors on cellular and molecular alterations induced by Apnea of Prematurity in the murine cerebellum.

## ISTW Disabilities and Integration 2022

Cellular and molecular alterations induced by Apnea of Prematurity in the murine cerebellum.

## Computer skills

Photoshop	
Cytoscape	
IMARIS	
R	
PRISM	
lmageJ/Fiji	
SPSS	
Python	

## **Teaching and Supervision**

From September 2019 to March 2023

#### **Supervision of Students and Interns**

Rouen University Mont-Saint-Aignan, France

- Supervision of a MSc intern during 3-month
- Training of several students rotating through the laboratory

From October 2014 to November 2015

#### **Teaching Assistant**

PUCMM University Santiago, Dominican Republic

- Topics: Anatomy, Embryology, and Histology.
- Lab and practical sessions

## Medical Experience

From March 2017 to May 2017

#### **Social and Family Medicine Internship**

Centro de Salud Integral Bella Vista Dominican Republic

HIV Clinic; Epidemiology; ER

From October 2016 to February 2017

#### Surgery and Pediatrics Internships

Hospital Metropolitano de Santiago Dominican Republic Surgery; Pathology; Oncology; Pediatric and Neonatal ICU

From August 2016 to March 2017

#### **OB/GYN** and Psychiatry Internships

Hospital Regional Universitario José María Cabral y Báez Santiago de

los Caballeros, Dominican Republic

Peripartum; Partum; Ambulatory / Consults

From May 2016 to August 2016

#### Internal Medicine Internship

Saint Barnabas Hospital New York, NY, United States Neurology; Rheumatology; Pneumology; Nephrology

#### **Practical Skills**

#### Laboratory and Experimentation

- Preparation and mounting of anatomo-pathological samples
- Bacterial culture (agars, selective media, antibiogram)
- Preparation and analysis of blood smears
- Molecular biology (RNA extraction, reverse transcription...)
- Laser capture microdissection
- Quantitative RT-PCR
- Pipetting system robot programming
- Confocal microscopy
- Immunohistochemistry
- Transparisation and tissue clearing

## Research and Communication

- Experimental design
- Statistical modeling (GLM, GLMM...)
- Scientific communication
- Theoretical and practical classes
- Writing scientific reports
- Scientific illustration
- Grant application writing
- Translation and simultaneous interpretation

# Surgery and clinical skills

- Minor surgery
- Pre and post-operative follow-up
- Complete physical examination
- Differential diagnosis
- Pharmacology